A Guide to the Furious Flower Poetry Center Records, 1990-2014: UA 0017
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Furious Flower Poetry Center Records,
1990-2014
Special Collections, James Madison University
James Madison University. Furious Flower Poetry Center
Joanne Gabbin
UA 0017
280
8.7 cubic feet; 13 hollinger boxes, 1 half-hollinger box, 1 record storage box, 1 oversize hollinger box, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 oversize flat folder
The Furious Flower Poetry Center Records, consisting of 8.7 cubic feet (13 Hollinger boxes, 1 half-Hollinger box, 1 record storage box, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 oversize flat folder), document the departmental activities of the Furious Flower Poetry Center.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Furious Flower Poetry Center transferred these materials to Special Collections on May 16 and June 29, 2016.
Other Formats Available
Digitization of media content is in-process as of November 2016. Access will be made available to content once digitization is complete, barring any copyright or use restrictions.
Administrative History
The Furious Flower Poetry Center (FFPC) was established in 1999 by Joanne V. Gabbin when she was the director of James Madison University's Honors Program. With this flagship of the Honors Program, she continued the kind of programming she had begun by hosting the 1994 Furious flower Poetry Conference, which was the nation's first scholarly conference on Black poetry. The event was met with overwhelming praise, and The Washington Post called it an historic event. In 2005, following the success of the second Furious Flower Poetry Conference (2004), JMU gave the FFPC its official charter, making it the first academic center in the United States devoted to Black poetry. Gabbin became its executive director, leaving the Honors Program after 19 years of service.
Today, the FFPC is committed to "cultivating, honoring, and promoting the diverse voices of African American poets by making the genre accessible to a wide audience and collaborating with educational and cultural institutions, literary organizations, and artists." It hosts visiting poets for readings at JMU and nearby venues; sponsors workshops; holds an annual poetry camp for elementary and middle school-aged children; produces texts, videos, DVDs and other materials on African-American poetry; and gathers poets and other scholars for intimate panels and seminars, as well as major conferences. FFPC has held three decennial Furious Flower Conferences: "A Revolution in African American Poetry" (1994), "Regenerating the Black Poetic Tradition" (2004), and "Seeding the Future of African American Poetry" (2014).
FFPC is located off of Martin Luther King Jr. Way/Historic Cantrell Avenue. Beyond her duties as Executive Director of the Furious Flower Poetry Center, Joanne Gabbin is a professor of English at JMU, a published author, and a member of the International Literary Hall of Fame for Writers of African Descent.
Scope and Content
The Furious Flower Poetry Center Records, 1990-2014, consisting of 8.7 cubic feet (13 Hollinger boxes, 1 half-Hollinger box, 5 oversize flat boxes, 1 oversize flat folder), document the departmental activities of the Furious Flower Poetry Center, a unit formerly of the JMU Honor's Program that became its own separate academic center of the University in 2005. A portion of the material contained within the records derive from events and programs sponsored by the Furious Flower Poetry Center including 73 Poems for 73 Years: Celebrating the Life of Lucille Clifton, Lineage: The Margaret Walker Song Cycle, and an annual children's poetry camp. Specific types of materials include event posters and brochures, exhibit panels, logistical and planning documentation, and email correspondence. Materials related to publications produced by the Center such as Mourning Katrina: A Poetic Response to Tragedy and Shaping Memories: Reflections of African American Women Writers are comprised of draft manuscripts and correspondence with poets and publishers. Grant proposals and awards, many of which relate to the aforementioned events and projects, are also represented.
While there may be overlap in content, materials directly related to Furious Flower's decennial conferences on African-American poetry form a separate collection – Furious Flower Poetry Center Conference Records, UA 0018.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into five series:
Series 1: Grants, 2004-2014
Series 2: Publications and Manuscripts, 1993-2012
Series 3: Events, Programs, and Workshops, 1990-2012
Series 4: Media
Series 5: Oversize, 2004-2012
All series are arranged chronologically; Series 2 and Series 3 are further arranged alphabetically within a particular publication or event. At this time, no particular order has been imposed on Series 4. Series 5 is arranged chronologically according to the order determined in the "home" series.
Related Materials
Furious Flower Poetry Center Conference Records, UA 0018
Separated Materials
A copy of Mourning Katrina: A Poetic Response to Tragedy Buena Vista, Va.: Mariner Publishing, 2009 and 73 Poems for 73 Years: Celebrating the Life of Lucille Clifton Harrisonburg, Va.: Virginia Tech Printing Services, 2010 were removed from Series 2, catalogued, and placed in the Special Collections rare book collection.
The following titles were removed from Series 3 and catalogued: Opala, Joseph A. The Gullah: rice, slavery and the Sierra Leone-American connection. Freetown, Sierra Leone: USIS, 1987; Opala, Joseph. Krio in a nutshell.: Krio Grammar with Lessons, Exercise and Vocabulary, Vol. 1. Freetown, Sierra Leone: [publisher not identified], 1991; Opala, Joseph. Krio in a nutshell.: Krio Conversation with Dialogues, Stories, Proverbs, etc., Vol. 2. Freetown, Sierra Leone: [publisher not identified], 1991; Geraty, Virginia Mixson. Bittle en' t'ing': Gullah cooking with Maum Chrish'. Orangeburg, S.C.: Sandlapper Pub., 1992.
Due to duplication elsewhere in Special Collections the following issues of Madison (known as Montpelier from 1977-2005), many with articles pertaining to Furious Flower Poetry Center, were returned to the donor: Summer 2003, Winter 2005, Spring 2006, Fall 2006, Summer 2006, Spring 2007, Summer 2007, Fall 2007, Fall 2008, Winter 2008, Summer 2009, Fall 2009, Spring/Summer 2010, Spring/Summer 2011, Fall 2011, Spring/Summer 2015. These issues were loose when donated and were not a part of any pre-established order or foldering system.
Bibliography
"Furious Flower Poetry Center." James Madison University. Accessed August 09, 2016. https://www.jmu.edu/furiousflower/index.shtml.
- Grants, 2004-2014 (Box 1)
  Contents
  Arranged chronologically.
  FFPC relies heavily on funding from corporate entities and non-profits to subsidize and off-set the cost of furthering their mission of promoting African-American poetry. As such, this series contains grant proposals and awards (all closed) relating to events, publications, and other projects sponsored by the Furious Flower Poetry Center. Projects represented in this series include "Dream in Color," an online curriculum sponsored by Target that enabled elementary, middle, and high-school students to discover the works of African-American poets; and the publication of Mourning Katrina, an anthology of poems by observers and survivors of Hurricane Katrina. All grant materials were removed from three-ring binders and foldered, maintaining original order.
  - California Newsreel, 532025 (Folder 1 of 2), 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - California Newsreel, 532025 (Folder 2 of 2), 2004-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TJ Anderson, Grant Closed,, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Poetry Camp 2005, Grant Closed, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rachel Malcolm Woods, 17 Stones Lost & Forgotten, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nikki Giovanni, Grant Closed, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Target - 550200 (Folder 1 of 2), 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Target - 550200 (Folder 2 of 2), 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Donnelly (PC), 550201, 2006-2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Donnelly (MK), 550070 (Folder 1 of 2), 2006-2010 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Donnelly (MK), 550070 (Folder 2 of 2), 2006-2010 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pomegranate, 532113, 2006-2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - COFCU - 550173, Closed, 2006-2013 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ACV - Dr. Goddess - 550232, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ACV Rutha Harris, 550274, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Clifton VFH, 550282 (Folder 1 of 2), 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clifton VFH, 550282 (Folder 2 of 2), 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Publications and Manuscripts, 1993-2012 (Box 3)
  Arranged chronologically by project date and sub-arranged alphabetically within each project.
  This series contains material related to publications and manuscripts produced by the Furious Flower Poetry Center. In many cases this refers to books in the typical sense (Mourning Katrina: A Poetic Response to Tragedy, Furious Flower: African-American Poetry from the Black Arts Movement to the Present), Furious Flower Poetry Center also oversaw the publication of The Painted Word – a set of notecards and a corresponding calendar of poets' portraits. Correspondence with various publishers is also included.
  - Oxford University Press, 1993-2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - UVA Contracts Furious Flower, 1994-2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - LSU Press, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Furious Flower Manuscript (Folder 1 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Furious Flower Manuscript (Folder 2 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Box 7)
  - Furious Flower Manuscript (Folder 3 of 5), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Furious Flower Manuscript (Folder 4 of 5), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Furious Flower Manuscript (Folder 5 of 5), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript - Greening (Folder 1 of 2), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript - Greening (Folder 2 of 2), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Defining Moments table of contents, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - FFPC Brochure 2006, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lynda Koolish Book Project, 2004-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Library - Books Desired, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Mourning Katrina correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mourning Katrina Submissions I, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mourning Katrina Submissions II (Folder 1 of 2), 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mourning Katrina Submissions II (Folder 2 of 2), 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mourning Katrina Talent Releases, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems A-E, 2005-2009 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems F-J, 2005-2009 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems K-O, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems P-T, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems U-Z, 2005-2009 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Mourning Katrina Poems not yet sent, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mourning Katrina Press, 2005-2007 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mourning Katrina JVG Writing, 2005-2010 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Katrina & Rita Articles, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mourning Katrina Contacts, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mourning Katrina UVA Press, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Praise for My Soul CD, 2006-2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mourning Katrina Background Information, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mourning Katrina Mariner Publishing, 2006-2008 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mourning Katrina Permissions to Poets, 2006-2009 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mourning Katrina CD Sales & Promotion, 2006-2011 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Mourning Katrina CD Project, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mourning Katrina Invoices, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Preview of My Soul is Anchored CD, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mourning Katrina Book Project, 2007-2011 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Mourning Katrina Promotional & Event Materials [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2008 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mourning Katrina book, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Mourning Katrina Draft Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Mourning Katrina Draft Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pomegranate (Folder 1 of 2), 2005-2010 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pomegranate (Folder 2 of 2), 2005-2010 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Painted Word: African American Poets, 2008 calendars (Pomegranate) [REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Painted Word: African American Poets Notecards (Pomegranate), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Intellectual Property Disclosures, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - JVG - Manuscript - Wintergreen (Folder 1 of 2), 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - JVG - Manuscript - Wintergreen (Folder 2 of 2), 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Shaping Memories Publication & Orders, 2007-2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Permissions - Wintergreen Book, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Shaping Memories, JVG Book Release, 2008-2009 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Wintergreen biographies and list of unedited essays, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Dream in Color Press [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Target, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Dream in Color Curricula, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Furious Flower Poetry Center - Malaika Favorite Quilt Portrait - 2007 Calendar, 2005-2008 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Dream in Color Lessons, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - FFPC - Target, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Permissions for Poems (Poetry Writing Contest), 2008 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Publishers' Contact Information, 2010-2012 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Events, Programs, and Workshops, 1990-2012 (Box 10)
  Arranged chronologically by event and sub-arranged alphabetically within each event.
  This series is comprised of material relating primarily to the many events, programs, and workshops hosted and sponsored by the Furious Flower Poetry Center. Major events represented in this series include Tell Me Your Names: The Poetry of Lucille Clifton, a week-long seminar held June 14 –June 21, 2009 and 73 Poems for 73 Years: Celebrating the Life of Lucille Clifton, a tribute program held September 21, 2010. Of particular interest are 57 oversize exhibit panels from Among Poets: Lucille Clifton Commemorative Exhibition. This 2012 exhibition held at the Reginald F. Lewis Museum and the Enoch Pratt Free Library, both in Baltimore, Maryland, primarily feature photographs by Lynda Koolish of Lucille Clifton, her contemporaries, and her family and friends. The Center's annual Children's Poetry Camp is also well documented. Researchers should note that there are some files in this series (e.g. materials concerning Oni Lasana Productions) that are not directly related to events held by FFPC. These events are likely ones attended by FFPC staff or documented because they serve as examples of comparable outreach initiatives or similar types of promotion.
  - Oni Lasana Productions Presents Adventures in Poetry, Storytelling, & More!, 1990-2009 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Programs and promotional materials, 1994-2011 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Joe Opala, 1999-2003 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - FFPC Press & Publicity, 1999-2006 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Celebrating Black Women, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Materials from Event binder (Folder 1 of 2) [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2000-2011 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Materials from Event binder (Folder 2 of 2), 2000-2011 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 2004-2005 Events [REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2004 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Shenandoah Valley Slam Team, 2004-2006 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Commission for the Arts, 2004-2006 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - National Poetry Slam, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - National Humanities Center, 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Truth Is On Its Way, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 2006-2007 Events, 2006-2007 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Poetry Readings & Performances [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2006-2011, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - FFPC - Education, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Richard Wright Project, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Literary Awards, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 2007-2008 Events, 2007-2008 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Visiting Speakers 2008: Dr. Goddess, Goes to Jail, 2007-2008 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Children's Poetry Camp [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2007-2012 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Visiting Speakers 2008: David Mills, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 2008-2009 Events, 2008-2009 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Events 2009, Children's Museum & WVPT Kid's Book Festival, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Poetry Month, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - National Poetry Month [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2009-2010, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Tell Me Your Names [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2009 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Tell Me Your Names schedule, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Audience Questions and Permission Forms, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Evaluations, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Expense Statement, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Facilities Management, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Information and Ads, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Master List and Contacts, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Miscellaneous Information, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Registrations, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Staff, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Tell Me Your Names Seminar - Web Information, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - 73 Poems for 73 Years, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - 73 Poems - Articles,, 2010-2011 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - 73 Poems - Bookstore, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - 73 Poems - Budget & Expenses, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - 73 Poems - Bulk Mail, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - 73 Poems - Contact List, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - 73 Poems - DVD, 2010-2011 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 73 Poems - DVD Requests, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 73 Poems - Facilities, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 73 Poems - Facilities, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 73 Poems - Giving Card, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 73 Poems - Invoices for Booklet, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 73 Poems - Lodging, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 73 Poems - Maps & Information, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 73 Poems - Parking, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 73 Poems - Permission to Use Poems, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 73 Poems for 73 Years - Photographs (B&W), 2010 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 73 Poems for 73 Years - Photographs (Color), 2010 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 73 Poems - Poems, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 73 Poems - Poets, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - 73 Poems - Poets Correspondence, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 73 Poems - Programs, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - 73 Poems - Reception, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 73 Poems - Souvenir Booklet, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - 73 Poems - Talent Releases, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - 73 Poems - Tickets, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - 73 Poems - Transportation, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - 73 Poems - Volunteers, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Writers at 73 Poems, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Collegiate Poetry Summit [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2010 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Furious Flower Poetry Center's 6th Annual Children's Poetry Camp Notebook, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Lineage, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Lineage: The Margaret Walker Song Cycle [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2010 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Society of America Awards Ceremony, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Women in the Arts, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Collegiate Summit, 2010-2012 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Continuous Fire, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Among Poets: Lucille Clifton Commemorative Exhibition panels [REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2012 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Sheer Good Fortune [SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO OVERSIZE], 2012 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - National Poetry Month, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Media, undated (Storage 0)
  No particular arrangement.
  This series contains various types of media including CD-Rs, DVDs, and magnetic media storage tapes. All media types are in the process of being digitized as of August 2016. Access to content will be made available once digitization is complete, barring any copyright or other use restrictions.
- Oversize, 2004-2012 (Box OV1)
  Arranged chronologically according to the order determined in the originating series with the exception of the Among Poets exhibit panels. These items are boxed together beginning with box OV2. Note that these panels are not individually foldered, but rather boxed loose. In this case, the folder titles are actually the title of the exhibit panel itself. Additionally, the date in parentheses represents the date of the original photograph while the item date of 2012 represents the date of the physical exhibit panel.
  The Oversize series consists of five flat oversize boxes and one additional flat folder of materials that do not fit within the standard Hollinger boxes. The Oversize series consists of materials that have been physically removed from their intellectual arrangement within the existing series due to their size and as such, the Oversize series functions only as a container list. Items removed from their original location were replaced with an acid-free separation sheet indicating the items(s) removed to its respective oversize location. The following folder titles are each represented elsewhere in the collection.
  - Mourning Katrina Promotional & Event Materials, ca. 2008 (Box OV1, Folder 1)
  - The Painted Word: African American Poets, 2008 Calendars,, 2008 (Box OV1, Folder 2)
  - Dream in Color Press, 2006-2007 (Box OV1, Folder 3)
  - Materials from Event binder (Folder 1 of 2), 2000-2011 (Box OV1, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Readings & Performances, 2006-2011, undated (Box OV1, Folder 5)
  - Children's Poetry Camp, 2007-2012 (Box OV1, Folder 6)
  - National Poetry Month, 2009-2010, undated (Box OV1, Folder 7)
  - Tell Me Your Names, 2009 (Box OV1, Folder 8)
  - Collegiate Poetry Summit, 2010 (Box OV1, Folder 9)
  - Lineage: The Margaret Walker Song Cycle, 2010-2011 (Box OV1, Folder 10)
  - Sheer Good Fortune, 2012 (Box OV1, Folder 11)
  - Among Poets: Lucille Clifton Commemorative Exhibition panels, undated (Box OV2)
    - Alexia Clifton as a child, born in 1965 (circa 1970), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 1)
    - Lucille Clifton with all six of her children: her daughters, Sidney, Fredrica, Gillian, and Alexia and her sons, Channing and Graham (circa 1960), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 2)
    - Opal Moore, poet, educator, and Furious Flower Advisory Board member (2010), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 4)
    - Fred James Clifton, Lucille's husband, whom she married in 1958 and with whom she had six children between 1959 and 1967 (circa 1970), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 3)
    - Lucille Clifton with her grandsons, Clifton Brown and Dakotah Brown (2006), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 5)
    - Young bass player in the Elliott Family String Quartet at the Clifton tribute (2010), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 6)
    - Hilary Hollady, educator and author of Wild Blessings: the Poetry of Lucille Clifton (2010), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 7)
    - Lucille Clifton, holding a photograph of her deceased daughter, Fredrica, with Alexandra, Gillian, Alexia, Bailey, Sidney, and Noah (2006), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 8)
    - Portrait of Lucille Clifton (circa 1960), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 9)
    - Haki Madhubuti, poet, educator, and founder of Third World Press (2004), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 10)
    - Hermine Pinson, poet, educator, and Wintergreen Women Writers' Collective member (2007), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 11)
    - Eugene Redmond, poet and founder of the Drumvoices Revue at Clifton tribute (2004), 2012 (Box OV2, Folder 12)